let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: " Who developed Python Programming Language?",
        answer: "C. Guido van Rossum",
        options: [
            "A. Wick van Rossum",
            "B. Rasmus Lerdorf",
            "C. Guido van Rossum",
            "D. Niene Stom"      
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: "Which type of Programming does Python support?",
        answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
        options: [
            "A. object-oriented programming",
            "B. structured programming",
            "C. functional programming",
            "D. all of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "Is Python case sensitive when dealing with identifiers?",
        answer: "A. Yes",
        options: [
            "A. Yes",
            "B. No",
            "C. machine dependent",
            "D. none of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "Which of the following is the correct extension of the Python file?",
        answer: "C. .py",
        options: [
            "A. .python",
            "B. .pl",
            "C. .py",
            "D. .p"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "Is Python code compiled or interpreted?",
        answer: "A. Python code is both compiled and interpreted",
        options: [
            "A. Python code is both compiled and interpreted",
            "B. Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted",
            "C. Python code is only compiled",
            "D. Python code is only interpreted"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: " All keywords in Python are in ___?",
        answer: "D. none of the mentioned",
        options: [
            "A. Capitalized",
            "B. lower case",
            "C. UPPER CASE",
            "D. none of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: "Which of the following is used to define a block of code in Python language?",
        answer: "A. Indentation",
        options: [
            "A. Indentation",
            "B. Brackets",
            "C. Key",
            "D. All of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "Which keyword is used for function in python language?",
        answer: "B. def",
        options: [
            "A. Function",
            "B. def",
            "C. fun",
            "D. Define"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "Which of the following functions can help us to find the version of python that we are currently working on?",
        answer: "D. sys.version",
        options: [
            "A. sys.version(1)",
            "B. sys.version(0)",
            "C. sys.version()",
            "D. sys.version"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "Python supports the creation of anonymous functions at runtime, using a construct called ___?",
        answer: "C. lambda",
        options: [
            "A. pi",
            "B. anonymous",
            "C. lambda",
            "D. none of the mentoined"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: "What is the order of precedence in python?",
        answer: "D. Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction",
        options: [
            "A. Exponential, Parentheses, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction",
            "B. Exponential, Parentheses, Division, Multiplication, Addition, Subtraction",
            "C. Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Subtraction, Addition",
            "D. Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: " What does pip stand for python?",
        answer: "C. Preferred Installer Program",
        options: [
            "A. Pip Installs Python",
            "B. Pip Installs Packages",
            "C. Preferred Installer Program",
            "D. All of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: " Which of the following is true for variable names in Python?",
        answer: "B. unlimited length",
        options: [
            "A. underscore and ampersand are the only two special characters allowed",
            "B. unlimited length",
            "C. all private members must have leading and trailing underscores",
            "D. none of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: "Which of the following functions is a built-in function in python?",
        answer: "B. /",
        options: [
            "A. factorial()",
            "B. print()",
            "C. speed()",
            "D. sqrt()"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        question: " Which of the following is the use of id() function in python?",
        answer: "B. Id returns the identity of the object",
        options: [
            "A. Every object doesnâ€™t have a unique id",
            "B. Id returns the identity of the object",
            "C.  All of the mentioned",
            "D. none of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        question: " Which of the following is not a core data type in Python programming?",
        answer: "C. class",
        options: [
            "A. Tuples",
            "B. list",
            "C. class",
            "D. dictionary"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        question: "Which of these is the definition for packages in Python?",
        answer: "B. A folder of python modules",
        options: [
            "A. A set of main modules",
            "B. A folder of python modules",
            "C. A number of files containing Python definitions and statements",
            "D. A set of programs making use of Python modules"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18,
        question: "What is the order of namespaces in which Python looks for an identifier?",
        answer: "C. Python first searches the local namespace, then the global namespace and finally the built-in namespace",
        options: [
            "A. Python first searches the built-in namespace, then the global namespace and finally the local namespace",
            "B. Python first searches the built-in namespace, then the local namespace and finally the global namespace",
            "C. Python first searches the local namespace, then the global namespace and finally the built-in namespace",
            "D. Python first searches the global namespace, then the local namespace and finally the built-in namespace"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19,
        question: "Which one of the following is not a keyword in Python language?",
        answer: "B. Eval",
        options: [
            "A. Pass",
            "B. Eval",
            "C. Assert",
            "D. Nonlocal"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20,
        question: "Which module in the python standard library parses options received from the command line?",
        answer: "B. getopt",
        options: [
            "A. getarg",
            "B. getopt",
            "C. main",
            "D. os"
        ]
    }
]
